{"test_questions": [[{"question": "How many inputs are required for a 1-of-10 BCD decoder?", "opta": "4", "optb": "8", "optc": "10", "optd": "1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most demultiplexers facilitate which of the following?", "opta": "decimal to hexadecimal", "optb": "single input, multiple outputs", "optc": "ac to dc", "optd": "odd parity to even parity", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One application of a digital multiplexer is to facilitate:", "opta": "code conversion", "optb": "parity checking", "optc": "parallel-to-serial data conversion", "optd": "data generation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select one of the following statements that best describes the parity method of error detection:", "opta": "Parity checking is best suited for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.", "optb": "Parity checking is best suited for detecting double-bit errors that occur during the transmission of codes from one location to another.", "optc": "Parity checking is not suitable for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.", "optd": "Parity checking is capable of detecting and correcting errors in transmitted codes.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A multiplexed display:", "opta": "accepts data inputs from one line and passes this data to multiple output lines", "optb": "uses one display to present two or more pieces of information", "optc": "accepts data inputs from multiple lines and passes this data to multiple output lines", "optd": "accepts data inputs from several lines and multiplexes this input data to four BCD lines", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When two or more inputs are active simultaneously, the process is called:", "opta": "first-in, first-out processing", "optb": "priority encoding", "optc": "ripple blanking", "optd": "priority decoding", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of decoder will select one of sixteen outputs, depending on the 4-bit binary input value?", "opta": "hexadecimal", "optb": "dual octal outputs", "optc": "binary-to-hexadecimal", "optd": "hexadecimal-to-binary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A magnitude comparator determines:", "opta": "A  B and if A  B or A >> B", "optb": "A   B and if A > B or A < b", "optc": "A = B and if A > B or A < b", "optd": "A  B and if A < b or a > B", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A circuit that responds to a specific set of signals to produce a related digital signal output is called a(n):", "opta": "BCD matrix", "optb": "display driver", "optc": "encoder", "optd": "decoder", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which digital system translates coded characters into a more intelligible form?", "opta": "encoder", "optb": "display", "optc": "counter", "optd": "decoder", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A basic multiplexer principle can be demonstrated through the use of a:", "opta": "single-pole relay", "optb": "DPDT switch", "optc": "rotary switch", "optd": "linear stepper", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a BCD-to-seven-segment converter, why must a code converter be utilized?", "opta": "No conversion is necessary.", "optb": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into gray code", "optc": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into 10-bit code", "optd": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into 7-bit code", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}